<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-3/metadata.xsd">
  <identifier identifierType="DOI"/>
  <creators>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Baldassare, Mark</creatorName>
    </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
    <title>Annual Survey of Orange County 1982</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>UC Irvine</publisher>
  <publicationYear>2014</publicationYear>
  <subjects>
    <subject>Pollution</subject>
    <subject>Noise</subject>
    <subject>Crime</subject>
    <subject>Growth</subject>
    <subject>Freeways</subject>
    <subject>Taxes</subject>
    <subject>Health</subject>
    <subject>Work</subject>
    <subject>Traffic</subject>
    <subject>Politics</subject>
  </subjects>
  <contributors>
    <contributor contributorType="DataManager">
      <contributorName>McKinley, Matthew J.</contributorName>
    </contributor>
    <contributor contributorType="Funder">
      <contributorName>University of California, Irvine</contributorName>
    </contributor>
  </contributors>
  <relatedIdentifiers>
    <relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="URL" relationType="IsSupplementedBy">http://data.lib.uci.edu/ocs/</relatedIdentifier>
  </relatedIdentifiers>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset">Dataset</resourceType>
  <sizes>
    <size>1199605</size>
  </sizes>
  <rightsList>
    <rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC-BY 4.0)</rights>
  </rightsList>
  <descriptions>
    <description descriptionType="Abstract">Orange County experiences considerable growth in the decade of the 1970s and is presently faced with the impacts of population changes as well as changes in economic conditions. The Orange County Annual Survey is undertaken by the University of California at Irvine to assess these changes and their effects on residents perceptions of community problems and the quality of life in Orange County. In this first year of the Annual Survey, the focus is on issues of growth and mobility. The sample size is 1,009 Orange County adult residents.

Online data analysis &amp; additional documentation in Link below.</description>
    <description descriptionType="Methods">The sample for the 1982 Orange County Survey consists of 1,009 randomly selected residents who were interviewed by telephone. The sample is stratified geographically, with half of the sample selected from North of the Santa Ana River, and half South. For data analyses, the sample is statistically weighted to represent the actual distribution of the Orange 
County population (see Social Data Analysts, 1982).
	The sample in each area was chosen using a computer program, which randomly generates telephone numbers from among working blocks of telephone exchanges. A working block is one that contains numbers in use. 
The total of telephone numbers generated within an exchange was in proportion to the number of residential phones represented by that exchange in the Northern part of the County or the Southern part of the 
County. Using this procedure, 2,000 telephone numbers from the South and 
2,000 from the North were drawn. This procedure of random digit dialing ensures that unlisted as well as listed numbers are included in the sample. Also, since 95% of the households in Orange County have telephones, random dialing yields a sample representative of the population of Orange County (Groves and Kahn, 1979).
	The Troldahl-Carter Method was used in randomly selecting which adult member of the household was to be interviewed (Troldahl and Carter, 1964). 
This method consists of enumerating the total number of adults in the house-hold and the total number of men in the household. Then, using a prearranged grid, the interviewer selects the individual in the household for inter-viewing.
	As further evidence of the representativeness of the sample chosen by the above methods, characteristics of the sample were compared to characteristics of the total Orange County population using the 1980 census (State Census Data Center, 1982). On the basis of age, income, sex, marital status, house-hold size, and home ownership, the sample is representative of the population of Orange County.</description>
  </descriptions>
  <geoLocations>
    <geoLocation>
      <geoLocationPlace>Orange County (Calif.)</geoLocationPlace>
    </geoLocation>
  </geoLocations>
</resource>
