<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-3/metadata.xsd">
  <identifier identifierType="DOI">10.7280/D1SG6J</identifier>
  <creators>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Kimball, Sarah</creatorName>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Lulow, Megan E.</creatorName>
    </creator>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Sorenson, Quinn M.</creatorName>
    </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
    <title>Establishment and Management of Native Functional Groups in Restoration</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>UC Irvine</publisher>
  <publicationYear>2015</publicationYear>
  <subjects>
    <subject>coastal sage scrub</subject>
    <subject>community assembly</subject>
    <subject>competition</subject>
    <subject>functional traits</subject>
    <subject>invasive species</subject>
  </subjects>
  <contributors>
    <contributor contributorType="DataManager">
      <contributorName>Kimball, Sarah</contributorName>
    </contributor>
  </contributors>
  <relatedIdentifiers>
    <relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="URL" relationType="Documents">http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/rec.12022/abstract</relatedIdentifier>
  </relatedIdentifiers>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset">Dataset</resourceType>
  <sizes>
    <size>118955</size>
  </sizes>
  <rightsList>
    <rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC-BY 4.0)</rights>
  </rightsList>
  <descriptions>
    <description descriptionType="Abstract">The limiting similarity hypothesis predicts that communities
should be more resistant to invasion by non-natives
when they include natives with a diversity of traits from
more than one functional group. In restoration, planting
natives with a diversity of traits may result in competition
between natives of different functional groups and
may influence the efficacy of different seeding and maintenance
methods, potentially impacting native establishment.
We compare initial establishment and first-year performance
of natives and the effectiveness of maintenance
techniques in uniform versus mixed functional group plantings.
We seeded ruderal herbaceous natives, longer-lived
shrubby natives, or a mixture of the two functional groups
using drill- and hand-seeding methods. Non-natives were
left undisturbed, removed by hand-weeding and mowing,
or treated with herbicide to test maintenance methods
in a factorial design. Native functional groups had highest
establishment, growth, and reproduction when planted
alone, and hand-seeding resulted in more natives as well
as more of the most common invasive, Brassica nigra.
Wick herbicide removed more non-natives and resulted in
greater reproduction of natives, while hand-weeding and
mowing increased native density. Our results point to the
importance of considering competition among native functional
groups as well as between natives and invasives in
restoration. Interactions among functional groups, seeding
methods, and maintenance techniques indicate restoration
will be easier to implement when natives with different
traits are planted separately.</description>
    <description descriptionType="Methods">Using different seeding methods (drill vs. hand seeding)
and maintenance methods (hand weeding and mowing
vs. herbicide) we tested initial establishment, growth, and reproduction of natives from seed mixes that contained
ruderals, shrubs, or a combination of the two.</description>
    <description descriptionType="Other"></description>
  </descriptions>
  <geoLocations>
    <geoLocation>
      <geoLocationPlace>Orange County (Calif.)</geoLocationPlace>
    </geoLocation>
    <geoLocation>
      <geoLocationPoint>33.7647 -117.7382</geoLocationPoint>
    </geoLocation>
  </geoLocations>
</resource>
