<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-3/metadata.xsd">
  <identifier identifierType="DOI"/>
  <creators>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Baldassare, Mark</creatorName>
    </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
    <title>Annual Survey of Orange County 1992</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>UC Irvine</publisher>
  <publicationYear>2014</publicationYear>
  <subjects>
    <subject>Consumer Confidence</subject>
    <subject>Housing</subject>
    <subject>Economy</subject>
    <subject>Social Issues</subject>
    <subject>Transportation</subject>
    <subject>Pollution</subject>
    <subject>Environment</subject>
    <subject>Senate Race</subject>
    <subject>Jobs</subject>
    <subject>Politics</subject>
  </subjects>
  <contributors>
    <contributor contributorType="DataManager">
      <contributorName>McKinley, Matthew J.</contributorName>
    </contributor>
    <contributor contributorType="Funder">
      <contributorName>University of California, Irvine</contributorName>
    </contributor>
  </contributors>
  <relatedIdentifiers>
    <relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="URL" relationType="IsSupplementedBy">http://data.lib.uci.edu/ocs/</relatedIdentifier>
  </relatedIdentifiers>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset">Dataset</resourceType>
  <sizes>
    <size>542747</size>
  </sizes>
  <rightsList>
    <rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC-BY 4.0)</rights>
  </rightsList>
  <descriptions>
    <description descriptionType="Abstract">The eleventh Orange County Annual Survey focuses on the timely issue of "Jobs and the Economy". The attention to jobs and the economy comes at a critical time in the county's history. After a decade of rapid employment growth, Orange County has had significant job losses in the 1990s. During this third year of the recession, local economic confidence is waning. This could have profound effects on politics, local attitudes, the economy and demographic trends. The sample size is 1,012 Orange County adult residents.

Online data analysis &amp; additional documentation in Link below.</description>
    <description descriptionType="Methods">The Orange County Annual Survey, UCI was co-directed by Mark Baldassare, professor and chair of urban and regional planning and, and Cheryl Katz, research associate. The random telephone survey included 1,012 Orange County adult residents interviewed from August 26 to September 2. We follow the methodology used in the 10 previous surveys. 

Interviewing was conducted on weekend days and weekday nights, using a computer-generated random sample of telephone numbers. Within a household, adult respondents were randomly chosen for interview. Each interview included 93 questions and took an average of 20 minutes to complete. The interviewing was conducted in English and Spanish, as needed. 

The completion rate for the survey was 64 percent. This rate is consistent with earlier Orange County Annual Surveys. Of the telephone numbers called, 21 percent resulted in completed interviews and 11 percent were refusals. The field work was conducted by Interviewing Services of America of Van Nuys, CA. 

For analysis, we statistically weighted the sample to represent the actual regional distribution of Orange County residents, as has been done in previous surveys. The 1990 U.S. Census population figures by city were reviewed for this purpose. 

The sampling error for this survey is +/- 3 percent at the 95 percent confidence level. This means that 95 times out of 100, the results will be within 3 percentage points of what they would be if all adults in Orange County were interviewed. The sampling error for any subgroup would be larger. Sampling error is just one type of error to which surveys are subject. Results may also be affected by question wording, survey timing and survey design.</description>
  </descriptions>
  <geoLocations>
    <geoLocation>
      <geoLocationPlace>Orange County (Calif.)</geoLocationPlace>
    </geoLocation>
  </geoLocations>
</resource>
