<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-3/metadata.xsd">
  <identifier identifierType="DOI"/>
  <creators>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Baldassare, Mark</creatorName>
    </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
    <title>Annual Survey of Orange County 1996</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>UC Irvine</publisher>
  <publicationYear>2014</publicationYear>
  <subjects>
    <subject>Consumer Confidence</subject>
    <subject>Income</subject>
    <subject>Economy</subject>
    <subject>Health</subject>
    <subject>Social Issues</subject>
    <subject>Police</subject>
    <subject>Recreation</subject>
    <subject>Libraries</subject>
    <subject>Public Schools</subject>
    <subject>Art</subject>
    <subject>Charitable Giving</subject>
    <subject>Media</subject>
    <subject>Measure A</subject>
    <subject>Politics</subject>
    <subject>Quality of Life</subject>
    <subject>Housing</subject>
    <subject>Transportation</subject>
  </subjects>
  <contributors>
    <contributor contributorType="DataManager">
      <contributorName>McKinley, Matthew J.</contributorName>
    </contributor>
    <contributor contributorType="Funder">
      <contributorName>University of California, Irvine</contributorName>
    </contributor>
  </contributors>
  <relatedIdentifiers>
    <relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="URL" relationType="IsSupplementedBy">http://data.lib.uci.edu/ocs/</relatedIdentifier>
  </relatedIdentifiers>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Dataset">Dataset</resourceType>
  <sizes>
    <size>468429</size>
  </sizes>
  <rightsList>
    <rights rightsURI="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International (CC-BY 4.0)</rights>
  </rightsList>
  <descriptions>
    <description descriptionType="Abstract">This fifteenth Orange County Annual Survey, UCI, examines several topics of recent relevance in Orange County and analyzes social, economic and political trends over time. The survey measures the extent to which Orange County has recovered from the economic recession and the county government's bankruptcy. It does this by analyzing trends in attitudes toward the economy, quality of life, local government, consumer confidence and personal finance. A special focus this year is to better understand attitudes about charity and charitable giving. Finally, it continues to track trends over time in the county's most important problems, transportation, housing and the political climate. The sample size is 1,000 Orange County adult residents.

Online data analysis &amp; additional documentation in Link below.</description>
    <description descriptionType="Methods">The Orange County Annual Survey, UCI, was co-directed by Mark Baldassare, professor and chair of urban and regional planning, and Cheryl Katz, research associate. The random telephone survey included interviews with 1,000 Orange County adult residents co nducted August 30 to September 8, 1996. We follow the methods used in the 14 previous surveys. 

Interviewing was conducted on weekend days and weekday nights, using a computer-generated random sample of telephone numbers. Within a household, adult respondents were randomly chosen for interview. Each interview included 96 questions and took an average of 20 minutes to complete. The interviewing was conducted in English and Spanish, as needed. The completion rate for the survey was 68 percent. This rate is consistent with earlier Orange County Annual Surveys. The field work was conducted by Interviewing Services of America in Van Nuys, CA. 

The survey sample was compared to the U.S. Census and state figures by city for Orange County and was found to represent the actual regional distribution of Orange County residents. The sample's demographic characteristics were also closely comparable to the Census and other survey data, including the previous Orange County Annual Surveys.

The sampling error for this survey is +/- 3 percent at the 95 percent confidence level. This means that 95 times out of 100, the results will be within 3 percentage points of what they would be if all adults in Orange County were interviewed. The sampling error for any subgroup would be larger. Sampling error is just one type of error to which surveys are subject. Results may also be affected by question wording, ordering, and survey timing.</description>
  </descriptions>
  <geoLocations>
    <geoLocation>
      <geoLocationPlace>Orange County (Calif.)</geoLocationPlace>
    </geoLocation>
  </geoLocations>
</resource>
