<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><resource xmlns="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://datacite.org/schema/kernel-3 http://schema.datacite.org/meta/kernel-3/metadata.xsd">
  <identifier identifierType="DOI"/>
  <creators>
    <creator>
      <creatorName>Rohit seth</creatorName>
    </creator>
  </creators>
  <titles>
    <title>Zinc deficiency induces apoptosis via mitochondrial p53- and caspase-dependent pathways in human neuronal precursor cells</title>
  </titles>
  <publisher>DataONE</publisher>
  <publicationYear>2016</publicationYear>
  <subjects>
    <subject>zinc</subject>
  </subjects>
  <contributors>
    <contributor contributorType="DataManager">
      <contributorName>Flex, Fastin</contributorName>
    </contributor>
  </contributors>
  <relatedIdentifiers>
    <relatedIdentifier relatedIdentifierType="DOI" relationType="Documents">https://www.researchgate.net/publication/268038321_Zinc_deficiency_induces_apoptosis_via_mitochondrial_p53-_and_caspase-dependent_pathways_in_human_neuronal_precursor_cells</relatedIdentifier>
  </relatedIdentifiers>
  <resourceType resourceTypeGeneral="Other">Other</resourceType>
  <sizes>
    <size>1380982</size>
  </sizes>
  <rightsList>
    <rights rightsURI="http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/">Creative Commons Public Domain Dedication (CC0)</rights>
  </rightsList>
  <descriptions>
    <description descriptionType="Abstract">Previous studies have shown that zinc deficiency leads to apoptosis of neuronal precursor cells in vivo and in vitro. In addition to the role of p53 as a nuclear transcription factor in zinc deficient cultured human neuronal precursors (NT-2), we have now identified the translocation of phosphorylated p53 to the mitochondria and p53-dependent increases in the pro-apoptotic mitochondrial protein BAX leading to a loss of mitochondrial membrane potential as demonstrated by a 25% decrease in JC-1 red:green fluorescence ratio. Disruption of mitochondrial membrane integrity was accompanied by efflux of the apoptosis inducing factor (AIF) from the mitochondria and translocation to the nucleus with a significant increase in reactive oxygen species (ROS) after 24 h of zinc deficiency. Measurement of caspase cleavage, mRNA, and treatment with caspase inhibitors revealed the involvement of caspases 2, 3, 6, and 7 in zinc deficiency-mediated apoptosis. Down-stream targets of caspase activation, including the nuclear structure protein lamin and polyADP ribose polymerase (PARP), which participates in DNA repair, were also cleaved. Transfection with a dominant-negative p53 construct and use of the p53 inhibitor, pifithrin- ␮, established that these alterations were largely dependent on p53. Together these data identify a cascade of events involving mitochondrial p53 as well as p53-dependent caspase-mediated mechanisms leading to apoptosis during zinc deficiency.</description>
    <description descriptionType="Other"/>
  </descriptions>
</resource>